Mss.Ms.Coll.97
American Philosophical Society
- II. Catawba, 3.5 Linear feet (Box 8-14)
  - South Carolina Historical Magazine, 1995; 10.0 p. (Box 10)
    Volume 96, no. 3 (excerpts). Includes: Thomas Blumer, "Record of Catawba Indians' Confederate Service" and Alexia Jones Hensley, " From the Archives: The Catawba and American Liberty."
  - South Carolinian. Catawba Indians, 1844; 37.0 p. (Box 10)
  - Tribes of the Carolina Lowland, 1972; 25.0 p.; South, Stanley A. (Box 10)
  - Catawba Games and Amusements, 1944; 11.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    Primitive Man, vol. XVII, no. 1-2. Annotated copy
  - Catawba Herbals and Curative Practices, 1937; 15.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    Journal of American Folklore, vol. 57, no. 223. Annotated copy
  - Catawba Hunting, Trapping, and Fishing, 1946; 41.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    Annotated copy
  - Catawba Medicines and Creative Practices, 1937; 11.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    From D. S. Davidson (ed.), Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Studies (Philadelphia Anthropological Society, 1937)
  - Catawba Nations and its Neighbors, 1939; 12.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    North Carolina Historical Review, vol. XVI, no. 4. Annotated copy
  - Catawba Religious Beliefs, Mortuary Customs, and Dances, 1939; 37.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    Primitive Man, vol. XII, no. 2. Annotated copy
  - Ethnoherpetology of the Catawba and Cherokee Indians, 1946; 6.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    Journal of the Washington Academy of Science, vol. 36, no. 10. Annotated copy
  - On the Catawba Nation and its Neighbors, 17.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 10)
    Manuscript. Annotated copy
  - Notes on the History and Bibliography of Catawba Linguistic Studies, 1957; 19.0 p.; Sturtevant, William C. (Box 10)
    Photocopies of original material from the Archives of the Bureau of American Ethnology, Smithsonian Institution
  - Siouan Languages in the East, 1958; 6.0 p.; Sturtevant, William C. (Box 10)
    Related Archival Materials note
    American Anthropologist, vol. 60, no. 4
  - Aboriginal Poetry, 1997; 2.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 10)
    Letter printed in Carologue, Summer 1997
  - American Indian References in the South Carolina and American General Gazette, The Gazette of the State of South Carolina, and The Royal Gazette, 1996; 8.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 10)
    South Carolina Historical Magazine, vol. 97, no. 1
  - American Indian References in the South Carolina Gazette, 1993; 2.0 Item(s); Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 10)
    South Carolina Historical Magazine, vol. 94, no. 3. Annotated manuscript draft and reprint
  - Catawba Language Alphabetical Draft Two, 1991; 42.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 10)
  - [Catawba and other Indian Words and Phrases], 18.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 10)
  - [Catawba Vocabulary / Dictionary], n.d.; 40.0 folders 1,974 pages; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11-13)
    - Folder #1. Absent to Axe, n.d.; 48.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #2. Baby to Berry, n.d.; 53.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #3. Better to Board, n.d.; 46.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #4. Boat to Breast, n.d.; 48.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #5. Breath to Cause, n.d.; 55.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #6. Chair to Come, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #7. Come to Cornsnake, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #8. Cornsnake to Dead Person, n.d.; 55.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #9. Deer to Dusk, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #10. Dust to Eat, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #11. Edge to Eye, n.d.; 34.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #12. Face to First, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #13. Fish to Foot, n.d.; 53.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #14. Football to Girl that I Love, n.d.; 53.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #15. Give to Goldfinch, n.d.; 45.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #16. Good to Good People, n.d.; 27.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #17. Goose to Hail, n.d.; 52.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #18. Hair to Hoe, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #19. Hog to Hunt, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 11)
    - Folder #20. Husband to In the Water, 56.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #21. Iron to Kill, n.d.; 49.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #22. Kin to Little One, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #23. Little People to Meanwhile, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #24. Measles to Mountain, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #25. Mountain Lion to Noon, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #26. North to Pain, n.d.; 53.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #27. Paint to Pod, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #28. Poisenous [sic] to Queen Snake, n.d.; 71.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #29. Rabbit to Rock, Stone, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #30. Roe to Say, n.d.; 52.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #31. Scaffold to Sing, n.d.; 52.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #32. Sister to Sole, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #33. Some to Stretch, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #34. Strong Man, Great Man to Tail, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #35. Tassel to Throat, n.d.; 52.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 12)
    - Folder #36. Throw to Turkey, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    - Folder #37. Turtle, Terrapin, Cooter to Want, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    - Folder #38. Warrior to Whip, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    - Folder #39. Whipporwill to Yellow, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    - Folder #40. Yellow-Root to Young, n.d.; 10.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
  - Materials and Words Collected by Wes White, 1982; 81.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
  - North Carolina in the Fall of 1754 with the Emphasis on the American Indian Population, 1983; 70.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
  - Reference Source Material, n.d.; 2.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    Excerpt of an unidentified bibliography, with a couple of notes added by Taukchiray
  - Transcript, Journal of Lady Liston, n.d.; 4.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    Taukchiray's transcript of the Journal of Lady Liston from the Robert Liston Papers, National Library of Scotland
  - Wascaw / Waxhaw Indians, 1.0 p.; Taukchiray, Wes, 1948- (Box 13)
    Notes on materials from Robert Mills, Statistics of South Carolina (1826), and Records in the British Public Records Office Relating to South Carolina (1711-1716)
  - Catawba Morphology in the Texts of Frank Speck and of Matthews and Red Thunder Cloud, 1984; 28.0 p.; Voorhis, Paul H. (Box 13)
    Kansas Working Papers in Linguistics, vol. 9
  - Indians of the South Carolina Low Country, 1562-1751, 1980; 2.0 folders; Waddell, Gene (Box 13)
    Complete photocopy of the book.
  - Indians of the South Carolina Low Country, 1562-1751 [Annotated excerpts], 38.0 p.; Waddell, Gene (Box 13)
    Annotated excerpts by Frank Siebert and Wes Taukchiray
  - Children of King Hagler, 1940; 10.0 p.; Ward, Bob (Box 13)
    Catawba Press, Rock Hill, SC
  - Catawba Indian Genealogy: A Report to the National Endowment for the Humanities, 1986; 76.0 p.; Watson, Ian M. (Box 13)
  - Men and Times of the Revolution; Or, Memoirs of Elkanah Watson, 1856; 23.0 p.; Watson, Winslow C. (Winslow Cossoul), 1803-1884 (Box 13)
    Excerpts of the work, with annotations by Wes Taukchiray
  - Letters to Lyman C. Draper, 1870; 4.0 p.; White, Joseph F. (Box 14)
    Photocopies of letters from an unknown source; touch upon missionary work with the Catawba, a Waxhaw settlement, and family/genealogy
  - Indians on Lumber River Descend from Cheraw and Keyauwee Nations, 4.0 p.; White, Wes (Box 14)
  - On Smallpox, with the footnotes, 1973; 14.0 p.; White, Wes (Box 14)
    Excerpt from Wes White, "Sewee and Santee Indians of South Carolina," South Carolina Historical Society
  - Papers of Wesley D. White, Jr., 1982; 1.0 p.; White, Wes (Box 14)
  - Revision of Wes White's 1975 Report to Dr. Sam Stanley, Center for the Study of Man, Smithsonian, 124.0 p. (Box 14)
  - Wateree Indians as the English Colonists Saw Them, 1670-1715, 14.0 p.; White, Wes (Box 14)
    Copied excerpts from the original held at the South Carolina Historical Society
  - Woodwards Westo Discovery, 1674, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 14)
    From Collections of the South Carolina Historical Society, vol. V
- III. Penobscot (Algonquian), 6.5 Linear feet (Box 15-27)
  - A. Ethnography, History (Box 15-18)
    - Abenaki-Iroquois Truce of 1678, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Acculturation among Penobscot, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Wabanaki Resource Book for Teachers (Draft), 1986; 2.0 folders 275 p.; AFSC Maine Indian Program. (Box 15)
    - [Algonquian Linguistics Comparisons], n.d.; 18.0 p. (Box 15)
      Incomplete manuscript draft of work comparing various Algonquian languages. Pages 46b-64 only
    - Bibliography, n.d.; 44.0 p. (Box 15)
      Includes bibliography; lists of manuscripts held by Connecticut and New York State Libraries; notes; map of the sub tribes of Long Island.
    - Analysis of Archaeological and Historical Data on Indian Occupation of the Mattawamkeag Area, 1985; Bourque, Bruce J., (Bruce Joseph) (Box 15)
    - Census and Genealogical Information, 1823-1893, n.d., 30.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Census of Passamaquoddy Indians, 1851; 10.0 p. (Box 15)
      Photocopy
    - Census of Penobscot Tribe of Indians as Given by Tribal Committee on January 2, 1935..., 21.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Census. Penobscot Indian Island Reservation, 1920; 7.0 p. (Box 15)
      Photocopy. From the Fourteenth Census of the United States
    - Conference with the Eastern Indians at the Future Ratification of the Peace, Held at Falmouth in Casco-Bay, in July 1727, 32.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Council of Peace, 1726; 15.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Proposals for Restoring the Penobscot Language in an Elementary School Curriculum, n.d.; 1.0 p.; Dana, Carol (Box 15)
    - Deed of Indians to the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1809; 2.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Description of the Countrey of Mawooshen, 1874-1875; 4.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Indian Place-Names of the Penobscot Valley and the Maine Coast, 1941; 272.0 p.; Eckstorm, Fannie Hardy, 1865-1946 (Box 15)
      Bound volume. Maine Bulletin, vol. XLIV, no. 4
    - Eliot Tracts Notes, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Ethnology Notes, 1938; 2.0 folders (Box 15)
      - Folder 1, 1938; 76.0 p. (Box 15)
        Micmac, Passamaquoddy, Ojibwa
      - Folder 2, 1938; 35.0 p. (Box 15)
        Beothuk, Penobscot
    - French Exploration in Acadia - Pierre Champdore, Marc Lescarbot, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Penobscots Override Council in Payout, 1996; 1.0 p.; Gagnon, Dawn (Box 15)
      Bangor Daily News, 14 February 1996
    - Genealogical Dictionary, Maine, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Assimilation, Termination, or Tribal Rejuvenation: Maine Indian Affairs in the 1950s, 1984; 15.0 p.; Ghere, David Lynn, 1950- (Box 15)
      Maine Historical Society Quarterly, vol. 24, no. 2
    - Letter to Newell Neptune, Circa 1901-1905; 1.0 p.; Hill, John F., (John Fremont), 1855-1912 (Box 15)
    - Historical Background of Indian-White Relations from the Earliest Discovery through the Participation of the Penobscot and Passamaquoddy Tribes in the Cause of American Liberty during the American Revolution, 20.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Hunting Notes, n.d.; 11.0 p. (Box 15)
    - Hunting Recollections and T. R. Peale Sketches, 1830; 9.0 p. (Box 15)
      Photocopy of article from The Cabinet of Natural History and American Rural Sports (1830, vol. 1), and photocopies of T. R. Peale Sketches of Penobscots (originals held at APS -- Mss.B.P31.15d).
    - Indian Supplies, 1836; 3.0 p. (Box 15)
    - [Indian Territorial Rights], 1.0 p. (Box 15)
      Manuscript fragment referencing Micmac
    - Indian Township School Records, 1835-1861; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 15)
      Photocopies. Includes Penobscot and Passamaquoddy records
    - Indian Tribe Names, 4.0 p. (Box 15)
    - [Indians of New Netherland and New England], 7.0 p. (Box 15)
      Incomplete typed manuscript, discussing the Algonquins of Southern New England, Long Island, and Greater New York during precolonial times
    - Indians' Book: The Wabanakis, 24.0 p. (Box 15)
      Includes Penobscot stories and songs
    - Instructions to Major Paul Mascarene, 1725-1726; 8.0 p. (Box 15)
      Print-out containing three documents related to Nova Scotia history: Instructions to Major Paul Mascarene from the governor of Nova Scotia; Articles to be Demanded of the Indians in Behalf of His Majesty's Province of Nova Scotia; Mascarene's Treay of 1725
    - [John Marsh Land Agreement], [1745]; 2.0 p. (Box 15)
      Photocopy. Marsh's Island. Hancock County Registry.
    - Calendar in Indian Tongue, 1982; 1.0 p.; Leavitt, Bud (Box 15)
      Bangor Daily News
    - Le Baron Jean-Vincent de St. Castin, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 15)
      Photocopy of page from unidentified work. In French
    - Les Abenaquis, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 15)
      Photocopy of excerpt from unidentified work. Includes biographical information on L'Abbe Louis Napoleon Joseph de Gonzague. In French
    - Lists of Heirs, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 15)
      Recorded by Charles Baily. Photocopy.
    - Maine Indian Claims Settlement Act of 1980, 1.0 p. (Box 16)
    - Maine Indian Program - Draft Materials, 1985; 67.0 p. (Box 16)
      Includes: Interview with a Micmac Man from Mattawamkeag, Maine; Bibliography/References; Medicinal Plants, Herbs, and Trees of the Wabanaki; Wabanaki Governance; Maine Indian Claims Act; Kennebec Father's Thoughts; Wabanaki Men, Women, and Children; Sixty-Third Legislature, State of Maine, Passamaquaddy Tribe
    - Maps and Family Habitats, 20.0 p. (Box 16)
    - Mascarene's Treaty, 1725; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
    - Micmac Indian Legends: The Loon Magician and the Flying Squirrel, 4.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
      Photocopied excerpts from unknown source
    - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Survey, 1825; 10.0 p.; Morris, Joseph (Box 16)
      Photocopy. Excerpt from a journal held by the Maine State Archives
    - Observations on Aspects of the History of the Penobscot Nation which may be Relevant to United States v. Maine, Civil No. 1969, 1972; 62.0 p.; Morrison, Kenneth M. (Box 16)
    - Newspaper Clipping, Murder, 1816; 1.0 p. (Box 16)
      Charleston Times, Charleston, SC. 16 July 1816
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1976-1984; 6.0 p. (Box 16)
    - Norridgewock Language Specimen in the Hand of Father Rale, circa 1720, 2.0 p. (Box 16)
      Photocopy of original in the Massachusetts Historical Society
    - Old Town Indian Directory, 1903; 1.0 p. (Box 16)
    - Notes on Penobscot Houses, Circa 1930; 1.0 Item(s); Orchard, W. C. (Box 16)
      Sieberts' notes on Orchard's article from American Anthropologist, v.11, no.4
    - Penobscot Bay Map, 1759; 1.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Bibliography, n.d.; 4.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Census, 1686-1994, n.d.; 10.0 folders (Box 17)
      Photocopies
      - Folder #1, 1686; 43.0 p. (Box 17)
        Photocopy. Includes People of the River Valley, Port Royal
      - Folder #2, 1689; 44.0 p. (Box 17)
      - Folder #3, 1698; 38.0 p. (Box 17)
        Photocopy. Port Royal
      - Folder #4, 1707; 16.0 p. (Box 17)
      - Folder #5, 1785; 2.0 p. (Box 17)
      - Folder #6, 1860-1899, n.d.; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
        Photocopies. 1860, 1864, 1874, 1877, 1880, 1899, n.d.
      - Folder #7, 1818-1994, n.d.; 8.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
        Photocopy. 1818, 1862-1865, 1870, 1880, 1923, 1975, 1993-1994, n.d.
      - Folder #8, 1935; 20.0 p. (Box 17)
      - Folder #9, 1979; 50.0 p. (Box 17)
      - Folder #10. Penobscot Census, Genealogy, 1780; 6.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Cultural Center Organization Chart, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Cylinders, 1.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Deaths, 1962 to 1988, 9.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Genealogies, 1979, n.d.; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Governors and Lieutenant Governors, 1867 to the Present, 1980; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Indian Calendars, 2.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Indian Nation, 1983-1985; 19.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Indian Place Names, 3.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Indian Population in Maine, Before 1820, 1.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Insects, Notes, n.d.; 19.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Nation - Tribal Administration, 1980-1988; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Record Book, 1817-1833, 63.0 p. 18 (Box 17)
      Photocopy. From the Maine State Library
    - Penobscot River Exhibit Meeting Outline, 1987; 1.0 p. (Box 17)
      Page burned; part missing
    - Penobscot Social Organization, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Treaties Notes, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Penobscot Tribal and Government Relations, 1815-1823; 40.0 p. (Box 17)
    - Porus, John, 1862-1877; 21.0 p. (Box 18)
      Pension, military records for Penobscot man who was a Civil War veteran. Photocopies
    - Les Abenaquis sur la Chaudiere, 1983; 72.0 p.; Provost, Honorius, b. 1909 (Box 18)
      Bound volume. Editions de la Nouvelle-Beauce, Seminaire de Quebec. In French
    - Registers of Baptisms, Marriages, Deaths, 1974; 2.0 p. (Box 18)
      Photocopy of bibliography cards of sources at the Roman Catholic Diocese of Portland's Archives
    - Report on Passamaquoddy Tribal Lands, Appendix, 1970; 9.0 p. (Box 18)
    - Penobscots Seek Solution to Financial Troubles, 1991; 1.0 p.; Ripley, John (Box 18)
    - Rosters of Penobscot Tribes of Indians for Fall 1815, 1.0 p. (Box 18)
    - Sale of Tribal Treaties, 1947; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 18)
      Bangor Daily newspaper articles (photocopies).
    - Sanger - Arrowheads, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 18)
      Photograph, "from Sanger article."
    - Sauvagesses de Restigouche, 1913; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 18)
      Micmac Postcard
    - Eastern Algonquian Prehistory: Correlating Linguistics and Archaeology, 1980; 14.0 p.; Seeber, Pauleena MacDougall (Box 18)
    - Senabeh, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 18)
    - Bomoseen, n.d.; 36.0 p. 2 copies; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 18)
      Incomplete
    - Moxus, n.d.; 62.0 p. 2 copies; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 18)
    - Penobscot Divination Customs and Beliefs, 15.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 18)
    - Taxous, n.d.; 10.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 18)
    - Wabanaki as Mariners, 1993; 24.0 p.; Smith, Nicholas N. (Box 18)
    - Report on the 1970 Excavations on the Penobscot Indian Reservation, 22.0 p.; Snow, Dean R. (Box 18)
    - Characteristics of Social Life, 1940; 30.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 18)
      Chapter from Speck's Penobscot Man (1940).
    - Penobscot Transformer Tales, 1918; 58.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 18)
      International Journal of American Linguistics, vol. 1, no. 3. Annotated copy
    - Stanislaus, Joseph, 1865; 14.0 p. (Box 18)
      Military records for Penobscot man who was a Civil War veteran. Photocopies
    - Stanislaus, Sylvia, 1937, n.d.; 4.0 p. (Box 18)
      Includes family tree and newspaper article
    - Brief History of Indian Legislative Representatives in the Maine Legislature, 1967-1975; 14.0 p.; Starbird, B Glenn (Box 18)
    - Susep, Frank, 1864-1891; 11.0 p. (Box 18)
    - Journal of Plans and Surveys, 1820; 2.0 folders 215 p.; Treat, Joseph, 1775-1853 (Box 18)
      Photocopy of original in Maine State Archives
    - Treaty Made by the Commonwealth of Massachusetts with the Penobscot Tribe of Indians, June 29, 1818, 4.0 p. (Box 18)
      Typed transcript
    - Treaty with Penobscots, 1796, 1979; 11.0 Item(s) (Box 18)
      Photocopies. Includes treaty between Massachusetts and the Penobscots
    - Maine, Composition and Characteristics of the Population, 1931; 29.0 p.; United States. Bureau of the Census (Box 18)
      Fifteenth Census of the United States: 1930
    - Working Bibliography of Sources on Maine-Maritime Indians, 1974; 59.0 p.; Walker, Willard (Box 18)
    - White Paupers on Indian Reservation, 1903-1904; 3.0 p. (Box 18)
      Photocopy. From Attorney General's Report
    - Woman's Story, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 18)
      Photocopied page of references and image of Native American woman only
    - Works of Frank Siebert for PIN, 1987; 43.0 p. (Box 18)
      Includes correspondence by Pauleena Seeber
  - B. Linguistics (Box 19-23)
    - Abnaki Dictionary taken from Sebastien Rasles, 1691, n.d.; 74.0 p. (Box 19)
      Handwritten notebook
    - Milicete Indian Natural History: A List of Bird Names, Together with a Supplementary List of Names of Other Animals, 1813; 11.0 p.; Adney, Tappan, 1868-1950 (Box 19)
      Linnean Society, Abstract of the Proceedings. Photocopy
    - Algonquian Glottochronology or Lexicostatistics, 1937; 83.0 p. (Box 19)
    - Algonquian Linguistics, 1938; 80.0 p. (Box 19)
    - Algonquian Roots and Words Showing Irregular Sound Changes, 8.0 p. (Box 19)
    - Dictionnaire Abnaquis-Francais, 1718; 10.0 folders; Aubery, Joseph, 1673-1755 (Box 19)
      Photostat
    - Dictionnaire Abnaquis-Francais. Transcription, n.d.; 11.0 folders; Aubery, Joseph, 1673-1755 (Box 20)
      Transcription by Siebert
    - Dictionnaire Francais-Abnaquis, 1718; 5.0 folders; Aubery, Joseph, 1673-1755 (Box 21)
    - Lord's Prayer in Wampanoag?, 1982; Aubin, George F. (Box 21)
    - Proto-Algonquian Dictionary, 4.0 Item(s); Aubin, George F. (Box 21)
      Notes by Siebert on Aubin's work
    - Bird Names, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Kinship Terms in Massachusett and Related Languages from Early Sources, 1981; 5.0 p.; Bragdon, Kathleen Joan (Box 21)
    - Classification of Birds - Rasles, Aubery, Modern Penobscot, n.d.; 7.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Contributions to the Proto-Algonquian Dictionary, Part I, 2.0 p. (Box 21)
    - [Penobscot] Vocabulary Notes, n.d.; 10.0 p.; Dana, Andrew (Box 21)
    - Vocabulary, Notes on Death and Mourning, 12.0 p.; Dana, Andrew (Box 21)
    - Tapes, Dana, Susie (Box 21)
    - Abenaki Vocabulary Notes, n.d.; 5.0 p.; Day, Gordon M. (Box 21)
    - Loup A Dictionary, n.d.; 233.0 p.; Day, Gordon M. (Box 21)
      Typescript. From source material of Father Jean Claude Matheret
    - Eastern Algonquian Notes and Dialects, 6.0 p. (Box 21)
    - English Words from Algonquian, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Enlargement and Revision of Penobscot Dictionary, 1990; 1.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Examination I on Penobscot, 1985; 3.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Change in Micmac Noun Possession, 1981; 2.0 p.; Fidelholtz, James L., (James Lawrence), 1941- (Box 21)
    - Narraganset Vocabulary, 1879; 3.0 p.; Gatschet, Albert S., (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907 (Box 21)
    - Comparative Algonquian, n.d.; 2.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 21)
    - Grammatical and Rhetorical Patterns of Word Order in Native Massachusett Texts, 1982; 2.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 21)
    - Leonard Bloomfield's Descriptive and Comparative Studies of Algonquian, 1987; 38.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 21)
      Historigraphia Linguistica vol. XIV
    - Primary and Secondary Stem Derivation in Algonquian, 1991; 30.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 21)
    - Some Micmac Etymologies, n.d.; 2.0 p.; Hewson, John, 1930- (Box 21)
    - Hospitality, Exclamations, Sayings, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 21)